Contact

sarah@sarahc-associates-llc .com

www.linkedin.com/in/ sarahcassociatesllc (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Travel Nursing Long-term Care Medical/Surgical

Languages

English

Certifications

Certified Legal Nurse Consultant

Sarah Curatella, BSN, RN, ALA, CLNC

VP of Quality Services at Bridge Senior Living Greater Birmingham Area

Summary

Sarah, founder of SarahC & Associates, LLC, has dedicated her nursing career to assisting and guiding seniors through the many transitions of aging. Her experience spans across settings such as long-term care, short-term rehabilitation, as well as assisted living and specialty care assisting living. Sarah is an ambitious nurse manager that, in practice, combines and applies her twenty-one years of clinical experience with her extensive knowledge in geriatric care management, administration, and wound care. She is determined to utilize the problem solving, analytical, and communication skills she has developed through her leadership experience and continuing education to assist attorneys in medical related cases.

Experience

Bridge Senior Living
VP of Quality Services
December 2018 - Present (1 year 9 months)
Birmingham, Alabama

SOMERBY SENIOR LIVING SERVICES, LLC VP of Quality Services
August 2017 - Present (3 years 1 month)

SarahC & Associates, LLC, Legal Nurse Consultants Registered Nurse, Certified Legal Nurse Consultant May 2015 - Present (5 years 4 months) Birmingham, AL.

A Certified Legal Nurse Consultant (CLNC) delivers cost-effective expertise to uncover the crucial facts from medical records. Services, such as interpreting medical jargon to preparing for court, enable the attorney to be fully educated and prepared for medical related cases.

We specialize in Geriatrics, Long Term Care, Assisted Living, and Specialty Care Assisted Living.

Services available to provide your firm with a competitive edge:

- Screen medical cases to eliminate the expense of non-meritorious lawsuits.
- Analyze electronic medical records, hospital policies and procedures and interpret their relevance to your case.
- Identify and locate the best medial expert witnesses to strengthen the credibility of your case.
- Develop reports and chronologies to highlight the significant medical events and how they fit into the overall case analysis.
- Identity adherences to and deviations from the applicable standards of care.
- Assist with discovery by preparing interrogatories and requests for production.
- · Detect tampering within medical records.
- Help assess injuries and identify causation issues and contributing factors.
- Attend and report on independent medical examinations.
- Prepare questions for deposition or trial examination (direct or cross).
- Facilitate preparation of exhibits and other demonstrative evidence.
- Research and apply the authoritative medical and nursing literature and standards of care.

If your caseload includes:

- Medical or nursing malpractice
- General personal injury
- Products liability
- Toxic tort or environmental cases
- Criminal cases
- Any other case involving medical or nursing issues, such as probate,
 Medicare fraud or workers' compensation.

We Can Help!

UAB Medicine Registered Nurse October 2015 - May 2016 (8 months)

Med-Surg nursing

Senior Care of Alabama Concierge at home Clinical Nurse Manager April 2013 - September 2015 (2 years 6 months)

Schmidt and Wallace RN Clinical Liaison September 2012 - April 2013 (8 months) Birmingham, AL

Country Cottage Assisted Living RN, Managing Director June 2008 - August 2012 (4 years 3 months)

Glenwood Rehab and Convalescent Center RN

June 1994 - June 2008 (14 years 1 month)

Med Nurse, Wound Care Nurse, Nurse Manager, MDS, Careplans, Restorative Nurse, Staff Development, Risk Management, Assisted Living Consultant.

Deficiency free facility.

Education

University of Alabama at Birmingham

Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2012 - 2016)